Contact

Flemingkatu 11A +358466301806 (Mobile) sharmagauravs08@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/gaurav-sharma-47706320 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Outlook

BPO

Benefits Administration

Certifications

Team Award 2017

Gaurav Sharma

Sr Software Enginner at Larsen & Toubro Infotech Ltd Helsinki, Southern Finland, Finland

Summary

Total 8+ years of experience in Java web development for Insurance, Telecommunication, HR Management System, Sales verticals.

Experienced in SAFe methodology development.

Skilled in Java software development from plan, code, test, build, deploy, release & bug fix with various tools and practices.

Ability to learn and adapt the emerging technologies quickly.

Ability to work effectively in team or as an individual.

SUN Certified JAVA Professional (SCJP) Certified.

Good Knowledge in OOPS.

Interests in Java8, MicroServices, Devops, and Cloud services.

Maven, GIT, Jenkins

Note: looking for immediate joining

Experience

Larsen & Toubro Infotech Ltd Sr Software Enginner September 2014 - February 2019 (4 years 6 months) Pune Area, India

Nordea Liv & Pension (Client for Larsen & Toubro Infotech)

Senior Software developer

Technology & Tools: Java, MicroServices (REST), TestNG, Git, Maven, Swagger, Selenium, CI(Jenkins), Jmeter, Oracle 12g, Eclipse, SAFe, Jira, Confluence

Responsibilities:

- # Major responsibility in development of Insurance Claims Handling Module including customer claim settlement letters and bank material generation.
- # Adding values to client through client centricity process.
- # Involved in laying foundation of micro services (REST) with responsiveness through different channels.
- # Creating micro services and testing through Jmeter for load testing.
- # Creating TestNG for Sonar code coverage for reducing technical debt.

- # Helping environment team for CI & CD through Jenkins.
- # Manage Team of 9 people, review their code and manage sprint release cycle by PI planning in SAFe.
- # Handle client interaction and adding values to feature development with efficient planning and business decisions.
- # Keeping track of new learning by taking sessions on smart programing, Peer programming, sharing knowledge on new technologies. Managing Induction session for juniors to help them tune with module and new business.

Infosys

Infosys Technology Pvt. Ltd. June 2013 - September 2014 (1 year 4 months) Mumbai

Technology & Tools: Core java, Multithreading, Servlets, JSP, PrimeFaces, JSF.

Responsibilities:

- # Development of Reliance Content Division Network (RelianceCDN) in Telecommunication.
- # Web Application Development in Agile methodology, of a Management Server in a Content Delivery Network (CDN) for an Indian Telecom/Datacom giant, to leverage media access via 4G technology.
- # Manage and configure various servers involved in the network and handle huge amount of content through the management server web app.
- # Involved in making LLD from Function Specification Documentation.
- # Direct Interaction with Client and SME for clarification of missing or ambiguity in requirement.
- # Leaded the team of 6 members.
- # Contributed critical role in EMS/LB/RAS/DS development.
- # Involve in business requirements, implementing and Unit testing the solutions for the application.

Aon Hewitt

Associate Software Engineer December 2011 - June 2013 (1 year 7 months) Mumbai Area, India

Technology & Tools: Core java, Hibernate, Spring, Multithreading, Servlets, JSP, PrimeFaces, JSF.

Responsibilities:

Development of 360Absence management FAMS (NucleusV5)

- # Involved in making LLD from Function Specification Documentation.
- # Regular Interaction with BTA and SME for clarification of missing or ambiguity in requirement.
- # Leaded the team of 5 members.
- # Contributed critical role in case/claim management and workflow details of case intake.
- # Involve in business requirements, implementing and Unit testing the solutions for the application.

Reliance Telecommunication

Deputy Manager

April 2010 - December 2011 (1 year 9 months)

Mumbai Area, India

Technology & Tools: Core java, Multithreading, Servlets, JSP, Struts 2.0 Responsibilities:

Carried a major role in developing & maintaining Sales and Billing Portals.

Education

JODHPUR INSTITUTE OF ENGINEERING & TECHNOLOGY

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Computer Software Engineering · (2004 - 2009)

St Annes's School

Higher Secondary School, Computers Science maths (2005 - 2005)

St Anne's School

Higher Secondary School, Mathematics and Computer Science · (2003 - 2003)